of coccidiosis.
Wimper heard nothing of this affair and the eggs were duly delivered, a grocer's
van driving up to the farm once a week to take them away.
All this while, no more had been seen of Snowball.
He was rumored to be hiding on one of the neighboring farms, either Foxwood or Pinchfield.
Napoleon was by this time on slightly better terms with the other farmers than before.
It happened that there was in the yard a pile of timber which had been stacked
there 10 years earlier when a beech spinney was cleared.
It was well seasoned and Wimper had advised Napoleon to sell it.
Both Mr. Pilkington and Mr. Frederick were anxious to buy it.
Napoleon was hesitating between the two, unable to make up his mind.
It was noticed that whenever he seemed on the point of coming to an agreement
with Frederick, Snowball was declared to be in hiding at Foxwood, while when he
inclined towards Pilkington, Snowball was said to be at Pinchfield.
Suddenly, early in the spring, an alarming thing was discovered.
Snowball was secretly frequenting the farm by night.
The animals were so disturbed that they could hardly sleep in their stalls.
Every night, it was said, he came creeping in under cover of darkness and
performed all kinds of mischief.
He stole the corn.
He upset the milk pails. He broke the eggs.
He trampled the seedbeds.
He gnawed the bark off the fruit trees.
Whenever anything went wrong, it became usual to attribute it to Snowball.
If a window was broken or a drain was blocked up, someone was certain to say
that Snowball had come in the night and done it.
And when the key of the store shed was lost, the whole farm was convinced that
Snowball had thrown it down the well.
Curiously enough, they went on believing this even after the mislaid key was
found under a sack of meal.
The cows declared unanimously that Snowball crept into their stalls and
milked them in their sleep.
The rats, which had been troublesome that winter, were also said to be in league with Snowball.
Napoleon decreed that there should be a full investigation into Snowball's activities.
With his dogs in attendance, he set out and made a careful tour of inspection of
the farm buildings. The other animals following at a respectful distance.
At every few steps, Napoleon stopped and snuffed the ground for traces of Snowball's footsteps,
which, he said, he could detect by the smell.
He snuffed in every corner, in the barn, in the cowshed, in the hen houses,
in the vegetable garden, and found traces of Snowball almost